Today, we're excited to introduce the Codex app.
Now you have one place to manage your
projects and delegate real work to Codex.
Instead of juggling terminal windows,
you get a single command center to
run and supervise agents.
Let me show you how it works.
On the left, you can see my projects.
And for each of them,
I can see the tasks that Codex completed,
and some of them are running live as we speak.
On the right, this is the main
conversation screen.
Let's start with this iOS app I've
been building.
It tracks the ISS in real time and
let's say I want to build new features for it.
I can type or better yet I can
just speak my mind and dictate.
Add a new screen that shows the
Astronomy Picture of the Day from NASA.
And that's it Codex is now taking care
of all that for me and
will figure out the right APIs to build it.
While that's running let's take a look
at another project I've been meaning
to migrate for a while.
Here Codex is updating all the
dependencies and in that task it's
even migrating from WebSockets to
WebRTC
for our speech-to-speech integration.
Now some of these tasks take a while,
minutes if not hours,
especially when you're working
on a large codebase. And
that's a big shift in how we build
software. Now you
can supervise your agents and
simply check in when they're done.
But let's go back to our first task.
Here you can see how Codex has been
approaching the problem
the steps it's taking and
the progress as it goes. And
it's done. Now if I click on
the right side I see the diff.
I can review exactly what changed in
the Swift code,
I can leave in-line comments for
feedback, ask for another iteration
or just merge if it looks right. Now if
I need to go deeper I can always
open the changes in
Xcode but in this case I'll just build
and run the app directly from here.
Working with the Codex app makes
building more fun, you know,
I don't have to
spend a lot of time editing code but
rather just thinking about how to
shape the app the way I want it
to be. Let's bring the iOS simulator on screen
and here it is. I just gave one
sentence to Codex and
it built this entire new
feature for me. Isn't that amazing?
Let's switch to another project I've been
working on. It's a web-based fitness
tracker. Well for visual tasks like this
one I want to stick closer to the
experience I'm building. So
by clicking on
top right corner I can pop the
conversation out like this and
bring Codex with me and I can dictate,
animate the bars to simulate progress
and now I'll be able in a few
seconds to see the changes
apply live, it really feels like
collaborating with a teammate and
here we go. Now another powerful
part of the Codex app is skills.
Skills let Codex connect to all of
your favorite tools.
In fact, this app was actually
implemented using the Figma skill,
which automatically used MCP behind
the scenes and set things up for me.
Let me quickly show you the design.
This is the homepage and if
I click one component,
for instance, you can see how the
spacing, the textiles and
all of that are defined right there.
So Codex has not been working from
a screenshot.
It's actually reading the structure
of the design file, including those
variables to generate real code using
our design system.
and that's why it matches the design so well.
Of course, you can also create your
own skill for yourself or for your team
so it can really fit your workflow.
Now, what's really powerful with the Codex app
is that you can even turn these skills
into automations.
Imagine you have tasks that you want
running at a specific cadence.
Maybe that's triaging alerts from
Sentry or bugs and tickets from Linear.
Well, you can now have that handled
in the background while
you focus on building.
There are many more features in the
Codex app, including working with
isolated environments
called worktrees, so this way you can
give each agent a copy of the code
so you don't have to worry about
conflicts or
breaking your setup.
You can also delegate any task,
especially the long-running ones,
to Codex in the cloud
with the exact same interface.
This was just a quick tour.
The Codex app is a brand new way
to build software.
For me, it means spending a lot less
time writing code and
a lot more time creating,
refining ideas and bringing them to life.
We can't wait to see what you build with it.